Guide to the Vassar Club of Philadelphia Records, 1903-2011
Archives and Special Collections Library, Vassar College Libraries
Vassar Club of Philadelphia Records
1903-2011
Vassar Club of Philadelphia (Philadelphia, Pa.)
6.8 cubic feet (10 boxes)
Archives and Special Collections Library, Vassar College Libraries
Materials relating to the creation and subsequent activities of the Vassar Club of Philadelphia.
Administrative History
The Vassar Club of Philadelphia was founded in 1903. From 1967-2006, the club organized the Vassar Show House which raised more than 3 million dollars to provide scholarships for Philadelphia-area students attending Vassar College.
Scope and Content Note
Materials relating to the creation and subsequent activities of the Vassar Club of Philadelphia. The first two boxes include materials of a general nature, such as minutes, reports, newsletters, pamphlets, directories, and correspondence. The other eight boxes contain documents relating to the Vassar Show House. Included are planning materials, newsclippings, brochures, scrapbooks, photographs, and other materials which provide information about the process of creating a designer show house, the programming surrounding each show house, as well as the histories of some of the houses themselves.
Access
This collection is open for research according to the
regulations of the Vassar College Archives and Special Collections Library
without any additional restrictions.
Subject Headings
Organizations:
Vassar College--Alumni and alumnae; Vassar Show House
Subjects:
Women--Societies and clubs; Interior decoration--Pennsylvania--Philadelphia; Decorator showhouses--Pennsylvania--Philadelphia
VCL Categories
Vassar College Alumnae/I Organizations
Encoding Information
Encoded by Laura Streett, December 2008.
Acquisition Information
Gift of the Vassar Club of Philadephia, 2008-2011.
Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements
The VHS tapes, floppy disks, and compact disks may require reformatting before use.
Container List
- General club records, 1903-2004, 2011 (Boxes 1-2)
- Show House — General, 1968-2006, n.d. (Boxes 3-4)
- Show House — House histories, 1967-1996 (Box 4)
- Show House — Publicity packets, 1996-2006 (Box 4)
- Show House — Programs, 1967-2006 (Boxes 4-5)
- Show House — Clippings, 1967, 1975-2006, n.d. (Boxes 5 and 10)
- Show House — Scrapbooks and photograph albums (Box 6)
- Show House — Decorator Show Houses, by Tina Skinner, Melissa Cardona, and Nancy Ottino (Atglen, PA: Schiffer Pub., 2004). (Box 6)
- Show House — Photographs, 1983-2006; (prints, slides, negatives, contact sheets and digital files) (Boxes 6-10)
- Show House — Posters (Box 10)
- Show House — VHS tapes (Box 9)
- Show House — unidentified computer floppy disks (Box 7)
- Show House — Flag (Box 6)